创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
想象有个地方 卫星90分钟可以绕地球一圈
Imagine a place where a satellite can circle the earth in 90 minutes...
度假的游客一觉醒来
where a tourist on vacation wakes up...
从太空酒店的房间里眺望出去
and takes in their view from a hotel room in space...
或者一片涂层成为了致命武器
or where a speck of paint becomes a lethal weapon...
会在航天飞机的侧面击出一个窟窿
able to blow a hole in the side of a spacecraft.
这就是环地轨道上的现实
These are the realities of Earth orbit...
通向太阳系
the gateway to the solar system...
它是宇航员的地盘
and it's the turf of astronauts...
太空垃圾
space junk...
终极寻求刺激者
and the ultimate thrill seeker.
和我们一起前往《太空边缘》
Journey out with us to "The Edge of Space."
宇宙:太空边缘
在不久的将来 人类将登上火箭
In the not so distant future, a human will board a rocket...
坐在开放的平台上
sit on an open platform...
升空120英里 直接进入环地轨道
and launch 120 miles straight up into Earth orbit.
穿上高科技的宇航服
Dressed in a high-tech spacesuit...
他目光透过石英涂层的头盔
he'll peer through a quartz-coated visor...
一览无余 尽收眼底
and take in an unparalleled view.
近地轨道上 景色壮观
Being in low Earth orbit is spectacular.
你举目眺望
When you look up...
看到漆黑的外太空和群星
you see the inky blackness of outer space and the stars...
星星甚至在白昼都在闪烁
the stars shining even in daytime.
低头俯视 你看到朦胧的蔚蓝色浩瀚大海
Looking down, you see the hazy blue glow of this gigantic ocean...
就在你的脚下
right underneath your feet.
这位观众是一位太空跳伞员
This observer is a space diver...
新一代终极刺激迷
a new breed of ultimate thrill junkie.
他解开安全带
And as he unhooks from his safety harness...
站在太空边缘
and stands at the edge of space...
看宇宙最后一眼
he takes one last look out to the universe...
纵身一跃 飞向地球
and leaps, speeding towards Earth below.
太空跳跃许多未来的想法之一
Space diving is one of many futuristic ideas...
安排在环地轨道上
planned for Earth orbit...
地球外围的太空区域
the zone of space that surrounds Earth...
起点在海平面120英里
and begins 120 miles above sea level.
这里是卫星及空间站的基地
It's the home to satellites and the space station...
还有 如果轨道旅行用品公司有自己之道
and, if Orbital Outfitters have their way...
将是终极极限运动 太空跳伞的基地
the ultimate extreme sport: skydiving from space.
环地轨道是通往宇宙的门户
Earth orbit is a window to the universe...
或许会成为地球本身的拓展
and perhaps will become an extension of Earth itself...
开展产业 探险 娱乐
for industry, exploration, and fun.
但是环地轨道上的环境完全不同于家园
But the environment in Earth orbit is very different from home.
这里缺少氧气
Oxygen ceases to exist here...
大气层
and the atmosphere...
那个护卫地球的保护罩已不复存在
that provides a protective shield around Earth disappears.
宇宙威胁窥视着勇敢的探险者
Cosmic threats lurk for those who dare explore here.
我们忽视了外太空是险地
We forget that outer space is dangerous.
我们忽视了在外太空 我们会碰上宇宙辐射
We forget that in outer space we have cosmic radiation...
我们会碰上太阳耀斑 碰上流星
we have solar flares, we have meteors...
会碰上太空垃圾
we have space debris.
那是外太空里的障碍赛场
It's an obstacle course being out there in outer space.
宛如自由落体跳伞运动迷
Like free-fall skydiving junkies...
跳出飞机 飞向地面
who leap out of planes and speed towards Earth...
太空跳跃可能貌似终极刺激
space diving might seem like the ultimate thrill...
但是其想法基于非常危险的意图
but its idea is based on very serious intentions.
乔纳森.克拉克博士 海军飞行医师
Dr. Jonathan Clark, a Navy flight surgeon...
前海军高空跳伞员
and former Navy high altitude parachutist...
是太空跳跃概念的推手
is one person behind the space diver concept...
但是也有其强烈的个人原因
but for very personal reasons.
我被分配到航天局太空部门工作时
I was assigned to NASA to work on space operations...
我的太太是个宇航员
and then my wife was an astronaut.
哥伦比亚号 休斯顿 超高频通信设备检查
Columbia, Houston, UHF comm check.
她牺牲于2003年的哥伦比亚号任务
She died on the Columbia mission in 2003.
虽然军事飞行员经常 会从陷于危险的飞机中安全弹出
While military pilots routinely eject safely from imperiled aircraft...
但是目前尚没有疏散程序让宇航员
currently there is no evacuation procedure for astronauts...
在灾难性事故中从航天器里弹出
to eject from a spacecraft during a catastrophic event.
约1%的机会
About one percent of the time...
我们会遇上主助推火箭的失败
we have a major booster rocket failure...
或者外太空的灾难
or a catastrophe in outer space.
或许跳伞太空服会成为新的安全装备
Perhaps the skydiver spacesuit will become a new safety device...
让宇航员用于飞行任务
for astronauts to use on missions...
其首次测试是16万英尺跳伞
and its first test is a 160,000-footjump.
为了安全返回
To survive reentry...
跳伞太空服有许多关键的特点:
the skydiver spacesuit has many critical features:
保护性连衣跳伞服绝缘了
a protective one-piece jumpsuit that insulates...
从零下40华氏度的太空环境
from the negative-40-degree Fahrenheit space environment...
到464度的返回高温
to the 464-degree heat generated from reentry...
每只手套上的小气流
small gas jets on each glove...
在失重过程中调整和控制身体
to orient and direct the body during weightlessness...
全封闭循环氧气系统可以再循环
a full closed loop oxygen system that will recirculate...
并且在10分钟的回家途中排除二氧化碳
and remove carbon dioxide for the 10-minute trip home...
锥形降落伞在接近地球时
a drogue parachute to stabilize the space diver...
稳定太空跳伞员
as they comes closer to Earth...
传统的降落伞将在3000英尺处打开 以安全落地
and a traditional parachute that will deploy at 3,000 feet for a safe landing.
旅程将是引人入胜的
And the journey will be spectacular.
在跳伞的开头两分钟里
In the first two minutes of the jump...
太空跳伞员会达到时速2500英里的速度
the space diver will reach speeds of 2,500 miles per hour...
进入自由落体
while in free fall.
大气阻力会将太空服...
Atmospheric drag will heat the spacesuit...
升温到474华氏度...
to 474 degrees Fahrenheit...
并将太空跳伞员的极限速度...
and slow the space diver to terminal velocity...
降低到时速120英里
120 miles per hour.
随着他的锥形降落伞在7分钟后打开
As his drogue parachute breaks free at seven minutes...
他开始减缓速度
he will begin to slow down.
最后 到了3000英尺高度
Finally, at 3,000 feet...
普通降落伞展开
a regular parachute deploys...
太空跳伞员安全落地
and the space diver lands safely on the ground.
那像是电影
It will be cinematic.
克里斯.吉尔曼是好莱坞的服装设计师
Chris Gilman is a Hollywood costume designer...
轨道旅行用品公司的总设计师
and chief designer for Orbital Outfitters.
他有一系列的太空服 是他为公司设计的
He has an array of spacesuits he's designing for the company.
他全身心投入在自己的剧装中
His passion for accuracy in his costumes...
终于获得了航天局真正的委托
eventually landed him a real commission with NASA...
设计女性的上半身宇航服
to design a woman's upper torso spacesuit.
虽然看上去服装非常合身
While looking at real suits very close up...
但是你开始了解到 它们不只是一件白色连衣服
you start to understand that they're not just a white jumpsuit...
配有塑料配件和泡沫头盔
with plastic fittings and a bubble helmet.
考虑到宇航服是个人航天器
Think of a spacesuit as a personal spacecraft.
为了保护身体 宇航服要逐层设计
To protect the body, spacesuits are designed in layers.
想象一下 你必须穿着这种衣服
Imagine the kind of clothes that you'd have to wear...
你穿行在撒哈拉沙漠里
if you were walking through the Sahara...
最糟糕的一天两次
on twice its worst day ever...
然后再挪步来到北极
and then make one more step and you're into the arctic.
那就是你必须穿的那种衣服
That's the kind of clothes you have to wear.
在考虑他的轨道旅行用品服装的...
And when considering the form and function...
形式和功能时...
of his Orbital Outfitter suits...
吉尔曼回眸了中世纪的盔甲
Gilman looks back in time to medieval armor...
来帮助创作未来的设计
to help create future designs.
这是我们14世纪的沙漏手套
Here is our 14th-century hourglass gauntlet.
那种关节弯曲几乎照搬照抄到
That knuckle bow is almost identical to the one...
宇航服手套织物覆盖层的里面
that is under the fabric cover in a shuttle spacesuit glove.
十分有趣 它几乎是完全一模一样的形状
And interesting enough, it's almost the exact same shape as well...
提供了同样的功能
and it performs the same function.
虽然太空跳伞可能还要数年才会成为现实
While space diving might be years away from becoming a reality...
寻求刺激者实际上已经找到自己的路子
thrill seekers are already making their way...
来到太空边缘 环地轨道的地盘
to the edge of space, the realm of Earth orbit.
2001年之前 绕地的特权
Up until 2001, the privilege of orbiting Earth...
保留给了少数精英:
was reserved for the elite few:
被选定在太空中工作的宇航员
astronauts chosen to work in space.
但那是太空旅游成为现实之前的情况
But that's before space tourism became a reality.
大多数人情系太空飞行世界的梦想之一
One of the dreams of most of the people...
就是亲自体验飞行
associated with the space-flight world is to actually fly themselves.
因此 太空旅游是人们从一开始考虑太空飞行时
And so space tourism has been an important component...
就一直是重要的组成部分
in people's thinking about spaceflight from the very beginning.
现在 太空探险有限公司
Right now, Space Adventures Limited...
是提供那梦想唯一的一家公司
is the only company delivering that dream.
我们是世界上唯一的一家私人太空旅游公司
We are the world's only private space travel company.
太空探险公司成立于10年前
Space Adventures started ten years ago...
当时第一个客户在俄国喷气机上进行了高空飞行
when its first client took a very high-altitude ride on a Russian jet.
他回来时谈到了好像
When he came back and talked about what it was like...
看到了地球的弧线 黑暗的苍穹
to see the curve of the Earth and the black sky above...
我知道我们会有大笔生意
I knew that we would have a great business...
世上会有...
and there would be literally millions of people...
数百万人想参与...
out there in the world who wanted to participate...
太空探险的体验
in Space Adventures experiences.
于是 在2001年 美国的投资经理
Then, in 2001, American investment manager...
亿万富翁丹尼斯.蒂托接洽太空探险公司
and multimillionaire Dennis Tito approached Space Adventures...
安排环地轨道之旅
about arranging a trip into Earth orbit...
私人太空旅游时代诞生了
and the era of private space tourism was born.
将丹尼斯.蒂托送上国际空间站
The flight of Dennis Tito to the International Space Station...
是意义深远的成就
was an enormously significant accomplishment...
许多人目睹了太空界的欢呼
and many people watching in the space community cheered.
他们认为这很了不起
They thought this was great.
那是新纪元的开端
It's a new age that has begun.
我热爱太空
I love space.
现在太空探险有限公司提供
Space Adventures Limited now offers trips...
3300万美元的国际空间站之旅
to the International Space Station for $33 million.
你会了解火箭
You learn about the rocket.
你会了解你要搭载的飞船
You learn about the spaceship that you're going to fly in.
你会了解空间站
You learn about the space station.
你会了解诸如太空中的生活 饮食 工作
You learn about what it's like to live and eat and work...
甚至上厕所等等
and even go to the bathroom in space.
要进入空间站
To get to the space station...
太空游客必须与俄罗斯人一起
space tourists must hitch a ride with the Russians...
搭载联盟号太空船
in a Soyuz capsule.
它已经成功飞行了35年了
It's flown successfully for 35 years.
这个人体工程学上的壮举
This great feat of human engineering...
不足8分钟就可以将你从地面送上轨道
will deliver you from the ground to orbit in less than eight minutes.
一旦送上空间站
Once delivered to the space station...
太空游客的生活就像真正的宇航员了
space tourists live like real astronauts.
舒适是相对的
Comfortable is a relative term.
因此如果你对野营感到舒适
So if you're comfortable on a camping trip...
那么你在空间站上会没事的
then you'll be fine on the space station.
如果你完全习惯于户外
And if you're at all used to being in the outdoors...
那里根本没有家里的舒适
where you don't have all the comforts of home...
那么你在飞船上会感到相当舒适的
then you'll be quite comfortable living in a spaceship.
食物很棒
The food is great...
但是你是不会为了吃去那里的
but you're not going there for the food.
太空的真正享受就是能够漂浮在失重里
The real enjoyment of space is being able to float weightless...
观看地球 成为未来太空探险实实在在的一部分了
and see the Earth and be really part of the future of space exploration...
能够感受到离开地球
and being able to see what it's like to step off the planet...
来到之前很少有人到过的地方
and go somewhere that very few people have been before.
你会看到地球整个美丽壮观
You'll be seeing the Earth in all its glory and splendor.
你每天能看到16次日出日落
You'll be watching sixteen sunsets and sunrises every day...
因为围绕地球跑得很快
because you travel so fast around the Earth.
现在 太空之旅...
Right now, taking a trip to space...
对大多数普通市民来说太昂贵了
is too expensive for most private citizens.
如果你就去近地轨道绕行地球
If you were to just go in low Earth orbit around the Earth...
那将要花费每磅一万美元
that would cost about $10,000 a pound.
你可是价值连城
That's your weight in gold.
目前有许多公司在设计新的航天器
There are many companies currently designing new spacecraft...
让太空之旅能负担得起
to make space travel affordable.
我无法告诉你何时到4000美元
I can't tell you when it will be $4,000...
但是我可以告诉你 它永远不会到4000
but I can tell you it will never be $4,000...
只要它一开始就是4000万
if it doesn't start off at $40 million.
不管怎样 太空探险有限公司
Regardless, Space Adventures Limited...
有了宏伟计划将自己的产品拓展到太空去
has big plans to expand their offerings in space.
我们未来的客户之一
One of our future clients...
将会进行首次太空行走
will be undertaking a space walk for the first time.
此外 我们非常兴奋
Additionally, we're very excited...
我们有绕月飞行计划
about our circumlunar flight program...
进行绕月飞行
and doing a flight around the moon.
他们会进入距离月球表面
They will come literally within a hundred kilometers...
100公里以内
of the lunar surface.
将老百姓送入太空
Sending private citizens into space...
改变了太空探险的模式
has changed the paradigm for space exploration.
我们真的 要我说
We've really, I'd say, banged down the door...
是开创了行业的新天地
for the rest of the industry.
现在有好多人感兴趣
There are many people now who are interested...
进入这个前沿领域 私下进行
in opening up this frontier and doing it privately.
我们希望看到在历史上作为催化剂
And we hope to be seen in history as the catalyst...
真正促使整个行业的开始
which really motivated that entire industry to begin.
或许太空探险中最令人振奋的部分
Perhaps the most exhilarating part of a space adventure...
就是前往太空边缘
is getting to the edge of space.
但是太空是个大领域 那里的威胁
But space is a big domain, and there are threats here...
完全不同于我们在地球上那个遇到的情况
that are unlike anything we have on Earth.
地球轨道 我们的太空边缘 一般分为三个部分
Earth orbit, our edge of space, is generally divided into three parts.
近地轨道是1100英里宽的地带
Low Earth orbit is a 1, 100-mile-wide belt...
最接近地球的大气层
that is closest to Earth's atmosphere...
始于海平面仅120英里处
and begins only 120 miles above sea level.
近地轨道有巨大的优势
There are tremendous advantages to low Earth orbits.
首先 大部分载人航天计划
First of all, most of the manned space program...
就发生在那个半径里
takes place in that radius.
1 0 奋进号航天飞机升空
One, zero, and liftoff of space shuttle Endeavour.
同时 间谍卫星 通信卫星
Also, spy satellites, communication satellites...
气象卫星都占用近地轨道
weather satellites occupy that low Earth orbit.
近地轨道如闹市一般 一派忙碌
Low Earth orbit is like a busy city, lots of activity.
哈勃太空望远镜 国际空间站
The Hubble Space Telescope and the International Space Station...
都将近地轨道视为基地
call low Earth orbit home.
联盟号和航天飞机在这里完成使命
Soyuz and the space shuttle complete missions here.
近地轨道上的物体和人
Objects and people in low Earth orbit...
绕行地球只要惊人的90分钟
can travel around Earth in an astounding 90 minutes.
45分钟在地球的向阳面
Forty-five minutes on the sunny side of Earth...
45分钟在地球的背阴面
forty-five minutes on the dark side of Earth.
休斯顿 你准备登陆 结束
Houston. You're go for landing. Over.
除了几次月球之旅
Except for a few trips to the moon...
人类探访太空都是在近地轨道上
all of humankind's visits to space have been to low Earth orbit.
近地轨道的底线是如果你到不了那里
The bottom line in low Earth orbit is if you can't reach it...
你就哪里都去不了
you can't go anywhere else.
人类太空飞行 最终 是要去别的地方
And human spaceflight, ultimately, is about going somewhere else.
近地轨道就好像是为此努力的切入口
Low Earth orbit is kind of the entry point for that effort.
近地轨道上方的区域叫做中地轨道
Above low Earth orbit is a region called medium Earth orbit.
这个广阔的空间在地球上方1200到1.4万英里
This wide stretch of space is 1,200 to 14,000 miles above Earth.
许多通信卫星发射到这里入轨
Many communication satellites are launched into orbit here...
包括全球定位卫星
including global positioning satellites.
GPS卫星的轨道大致在地球的1.2万英里高度
GPS satellites roughly orbit the Earth at about 12,000 miles...
那被我们称为半同步轨道
what we call a semi-synchronous orbit.
所以基本上它们每天绕地球两圈
So, basically, they orbit the Earth twice per day...
每圈12小时
once every 12 hours.
GPS安排在6个轨道平面上
GPS is set up into six orbital planes.
因此你可以想象到 在一个球形里有六个轨道
So if you can imagine a globe, there are six orbits...
被安排等距离围绕地球
positioned in equal spacing around the Earth...
每一个轨道面上大约有4到5个卫星
with roughly four or five satellites per orbital plane.
基本上让我们覆盖了整个地球
And basically that gives us coverage around the world.
GPS位于这样的高度
GPS satellites sit at this altitude...
结果就有多颗卫星每时每刻都监视着
so that multiple satellites are in view...
地球上的某个点
from one location on Earth at any time of day.
需要有4颗卫星来让你定位
It takes four satellites to get you your exact location.
第一颗会给你一个环状区域
The first will give you a roundabout area...
第二颗会对其进一步精确 第三颗也同样如此
the second one will refine it, as well as the third...
最后第四颗会说 你确实在那里
and finally the fourth says, "You are exactly here."
中地轨道同时也是充满危险的
Medium Earth orbit is also home...
范艾伦辐射带的所在地
to the treacherous Van Allen radiation belts.
这些高能粒子带
These belts of high-energy charged particles...
可以让价值3亿美元的卫星发射失控
can send a $300-million satellite spiraling out of control...
或给人类带来致命的辐射
or give a human being a fatal dose of radiation.
这些辐射带像细长的环伸出地球
These belts stretch out from Earth like elongated rings.
卫星被精确放置在特定的高度
Satellites are carefully placed in specific altitudes...
以避免来自太阳的这些致命的粒子带
to avoid these destructive belts of particles from the Sun.
进一步往外就是高地轨道 即地球同步轨道
Even farther out lies high Earth orbit or geosynchronous orbit.
如果说近地轨道是闹市的话 那么高地轨道就是乡村了
If low Earth orbit is a busy city, high Earth orbit is rural farmland.
高出海平面2.2万到3.5万英里
22,000 to 35,000 miles above sea level...
高踞地球的卫星
satellites hover above Earth...
在遥远的有利位置上一览无余
taking in an unparalleled view from a distant vantage point.
在这里 2000多颗卫星将高地轨道视为基地
Here, over 2,000 satellites call high Earth orbit home.
这些卫星似乎静止不动
These satellites appear to be stationary.
它们每24小时绕行地球一圈
They make a circuit around the Earth every 24 hours...
但是我们也是一样
but so do we.
这样我们就有了一个错觉
So we have the optical illusion...
卫星就定位在了外太空的那里了
that the satellites are sitting there in outer space.
但是为了到达地球轨道
But in order to reach Earth orbit...
物体必须首先离开地面运送至太空
an object must first leave the ground and be delivered into space.
要做到这一点 火箭或航天器
To to this, a rocket or spacecraft...
必须达到适当的速度
needs to achieve the appropriate speed...
抵达目标方向和高度
and hit a target direction and altitude.
时速几英里太慢了
Go even a few miles per hour too slow...
重力和大气阻力
and the forces of gravity and drag of the atmosphere...
会将航天器拉下来 坠落地面
will pull a spacecraft down, crashing it to the ground.
因此想法就是摆脱低大气层的阻力
So the idea is to get out of the drag of the lower atmosphere...
克服所有的涡流和摩擦
beyond all that turbulence and friction...
然后开始加速奔向正确的方向
and then start racing for the right direction and speed...
前提是你已经越过可感大气
after you get up above the sensible atmosphere.
很好理解为何航天器的发射是垂直升空
And there's a very good reason why spacecraft launch straight up...
而不是像飞机那样有一个角度
rather than at an angle like an airplane.
因此典型的航天发射
So what typical space launches do...
就是直线升空穿越大气层
is go straight up through the atmosphere...
穿越最初的最厚的大气层
to get through the thickest part initially...
然后它们弧形爬行几英里
and then they begin to arc over a few miles up...
然后开始加速
and then start to increase their velocity...
对准预定的方向
in the desired direction.
要达到目标轨道
To reach a target orbit...
航天器必须达到时速1.75万英里
a spacecraft must travel 17,500 miles per hour...
按照特定的弹道从地面抵达预定的高度
and follow a specific trajectory from the ground to desired altitude.
即使是一度的偏离 航天器最终都会进入错误的轨道
Even one degree off and a spacecraft will end up in the wrong orbit.
经过8分钟的飞行 烧掉了数百万加仑燃料
After an eight-minute ride and millions of gallons of fuel burned...
航天器现在入轨了
a spacecraft is now in orbit.
轨道是围绕另一个物体的周而复始的路径
An orbit is a reoccurring path around another object.
如地球围绕太阳旋转一样
Like Earth revolving around the Sun...
卫星和航天器被引力束缚在轨道上
a satellite or spacecraft is held in orbit by gravity.
地球的质量产生的万有引力
Earth's mass creates a gravitational force...
偏转了物体的直线路径
that deflects an object's path from a straight line.
可以假定地球的引力
It might be assumed that Earth's gravitational pull...
在这样的高空会失去其很大的影响
loses much of its influence this high in the sky...
但是在近地轨道上
but in low Earth orbit...
地球的引力
Earth's gravity is only two percent less powerful...
只比地球表面上少2%
than it is on the surface of the planet.
你滞留轨道的办法
The way you stay in orbit...
就是要达到足够高的速度
is to go at a high enough speed or velocity...
你在不停地落向地球
that you are falling back to the Earth...
但是你速度飞快 你弯曲的轨道
but you're going so fast that your curved path...
实际上永远不会碰上弯曲的地球表面的
actually never strikes the curved surface of the Earth.
你只要失重保持着围绕地球下降
You just keep falling around the world over and over again.
这样你就不会脱离引力
So you're not leaving the gravity behind...
但是你会依靠引力不停地围绕星球打转
but you're being spun around the planet by gravity.
就是它将你锁定在围绕星球的圆形轨道上
It's what's holding you in this circular path around the planet...
一直在把你拉回地球
and it's making you fall back to Earth.
理论上 物体可以永远滞留在轨道上
In theory, objects can stay in orbit forever...
只要它们有足够的速度
as long as they have enough speed...
去抵抗地球的引力
to resist the pull of Earth's gravity.
有两种轨道 圆形和椭圆形
There are two types of orbits, circular and elliptical.
圆形轨道支持卫星或航天器
Circular orbits are for satellites or spacecraft...
维持恒定的高度的需要
that need to maintain a consistent altitude...
有规律地绕行地球
and travel in a regular circle around Earth.
测绘卫星 GPS 气象卫星
Mapping satellites, GPS, and weather satellites...
都是用圆形轨道
all use circular orbits.
椭圆轨道就是椭圆形的
Elliptical orbits are oval in shape.
它们用在部分轨道需要较高的高度
They're used when a high altitude is needed for part of the orbit...
但不必一直保持在较高高度的圆形轨道上
without having to go all the way to high-altitude circular orbit.
航天器发送卫星进入高轨道
Spacecraft delivering satellites into high orbits...
利用椭圆轨道来送出荷载
use elliptical orbits to deliver their payloads.
无论是穿行在圆形还是椭圆轨道上
Whether traveling in a circle or an elliptical path...
地球轨道上有许多东西是充满危险的
there are many things in Earth orbit that are dangerous.
2007年10月 美国海军用巡航导弹击落了
In October 2007, the U.S. Navy shot down...
一颗退役的卫星
an out-of-service satellite with a cruise missile...
赶在了它返回大气层之前
before it re-entered the atmosphere.
原因何在?
The reason?
该卫星搭载有有害物质
The satellite carried hazardous material onboard...
如果它坠落地面 会毒害数以千计的人
and, had it crashed to the ground, could have poisoned thousands.
那种有害物质是1000磅联氨
That hazardous material was 1,000 pounds of hydrazine...
那是一种标准的推进剂
which is a standard propellant.
该行动被称为"燃霜行动"
The operation was called "Burnt Frost"...
这是迄今为止最复杂的行动
and it was the most elaborate effort thus far...
用来防备世界上日益严重的问题
to protect the world from a serious yet growing problem...
即所谓的太空碎片 或太空垃圾
called space debris or space junk.
太空垃圾是指人造的
Space junk is anything that's manmade...
放入太空但不再发挥作用的东西
that was put into space and is no longer functioning.
只要我们到过太空 就会有垃圾在上头
We've got junk that's been up there for as long as we've been in space.
就像垃圾慢慢堆积成垃圾场一样
Like a junkyard slowly becoming cluttered with debris...
从1957年发射第一颗卫星开始
from the first launch of Sputnik in 1957...
垃圾就逐步堆积在地球周围
debris has steadily been accumulating around planet Earth.
进入太空竞赛50余年
Fifty years into the space race...
我们的天堂里扔满了我们的垃圾
we have littered the heavens with our garbage.
现在 堆积了2万多个碎片
And now, about 20,000 pieces later...
地球轨道已经变成了一个致命的 垃圾遍天的垃圾场
Earth orbit has turned into a deadly, debris-filled junkyard.
看上去地球像是被一群蜜蜂团团围住
It looks like the Earth is surrounded by a hive of bees.
太空垃圾的大部分是火箭碎片
Most of the space debris includes shards of rockets...
不再发挥作用的卫星
satellites that no longer function...
以及物体升空后爆炸的碎片
or pieces of an object that have broken up after a launch.
受控于地球的引力
Caught in Earth's gravitational pull...
这些碎片穿行速度超过了时速2.2万英里
these pieces are traveling upwards of 22,000 miles per hour.
可以这么说 速度超过了子弹的10倍还多
Say, more than ten times faster than a bullet.
运动中的物体之间的碰撞
A collision between functioning objects...
诸如卫星或载人航天器与太空垃圾相撞
such as satellites or inhabited spacecraft and space junk...
将会是灾难性的
could be catastrophic.
联合太空作战中心 简称JSPOC
The Joint Space Operations Center, or JSPOC...
是绝密的空军监视单位
is a top-secret Air Force surveillance unit...
其业务是...
that makes it their business...
跟踪围绕地球的每一个物体...
to track every object that orbits around Earth...
包括太空垃圾
including space debris.
我们利用世界各地的各种传感器
We use a number of different sensors around the world...
称为太空监视网
known as the Space Surveillance Network.
这是世界各地29个台站组成的网络
It's a network of 29 stations all around the globe...
有雷达 还有光学望远镜
radars as well as optical telescopes...
来跟踪太空中的1.8万多个人造物体
that track over 18,000 manmade objects in space.
其中包括在用的卫星 也有报废的卫星
That includes active satellites, as well as dead satellites...
还有发射后的火箭箭体
and then rocket bodies that were associated with those launches...
以及碎片 就是脱落的东西
as well as debris, things that have just shed off.
如果它们彼此碰撞
lf they were to run into each other...
真的会是灾难性的碰头
it really would be a catastrophic conjunction.
要让JSPOC跟踪到
To be tracked by JSPOC...
碎片必须至少要有两英寸宽
debris must be at least two inches wide.
有许多较小的物体是无法跟踪到的
There are much smaller objects that cannot be tracked.
在我多数航天飞行中
On most of my shuttle flights...
我们一直看到窗外有小碎片
we always saw small pits in the windows...
大小如铅笔尖
about the size of a pencil point.
碎片数量最多是在近地轨道里
The highest population of debris are in low Earth orbit.
2008年 两颗卫星的蓄意碰撞
And in 2008, an intentional collision between two satellites...
引起了国际公愤 产生了碎片云
created an international outrage and a cloud of debris...
对近地轨道的威胁前所未有
that threatened low Earth orbit like never before.
我们的太空边缘是地球轨道
Our edge of space is Earth orbit...
太空旅游和探险的新天地
a new frontier for space tourism and exploration.
但是危机四伏: 太空垃圾
But danger lurks here: space debris...
空前威胁我们的航天器和卫星
and it threatens our spacecraft and satellites like never before.
2007年 太空垃圾的预计总量
In 2007, the total estimated amount of space debris...
有2万个 其中1.4万是可跟踪的
was 20,000 pieces, 14,000 of which were trackable.
当时 到了2008年 中国的航天计划
Then, in 2008, China's space program...
故意将两颗卫星进行撞击 作为反卫星试验
intentionally crashed two satellites together as an anti-satellite test.
国际航天界一片哗然
The international space community was outraged.
截至2007年1月10日
By the 10th of January of 2007...
我们所跟踪的物体数量
the number of objects we were tracking...
少于1.4万
was less than 14,000.
而到了16个月后
Here we are, 16 months later,
我们把数目增加了三成 超过了1.8万
and we've increased that number by over 30 percent, to over 18,000.
太空垃圾问题持续增加
The problem of space debris continues to grow.
碰撞已经发生在了
And collisions have already occurred...
太空垃圾与在用物体之间了
between space junk and functioning objects.
其中之一是一件碎片
One of them was a piece of debris...
撞上了航天器上的重力臂
that struck a gravitation boom on a spacecraft...
是在吊杆上的
severed the boom.
为了避免将来发生碰撞
To avoid future collisions...
JSPOC保持着联系航天局
JSPOC is in constant contact with NASA...
和其他国际航天组织
and other international space entities...
一旦有航天器或卫星可能遭到威胁 就通知他们
to inform them when a spacecraft or satellite might be threatened...
以使航天器
so that the spacecraft...
可以回避太空垃圾
could be maneuvered around the space debris...
就像船只回避航道上的威胁那样
much like a boat maneuvers around hazards in a waterway.
在这水下
Beneath the surface of the water here...
你无法觉察到的是
what you can't see...
实际会给你造成的最大危害
is what's going to actually give you the most damage...
如果我们遇上水下的木头或障碍物
if we run into a log or a snag beneath the surface.
在轨道上 我们面临着同样的问题
And in orbit, that's the same problem that we face.
我们不可能跟踪所有可能瘫痪或报废
We don't track all the debris...
你的航天器的碎片
that could actually cripple or kill your spacecraft...
我们面对的事实 就是你只是
and we rely on the fact that you're just...
不可能统计到每一片碎片来保护你
statistically unlikely to hit a piece of debris to protect you...
保单有朝一日是会失效的
and that insurance policy is going to run out someday.
幸运的是 迄今尚未发生过载人航天器
Fortunately, there haven't been any catastrophic collisions...
与太空垃圾之间的任何碰撞
between inhabited spacecraft and space debris...yet.
我们还从未见到过有载人航天器
We've never seen a human-piloted spacecraft...
撞上轨道垃圾而造成危害
run into orbital debris and been damaged...
但是我们曾有过一些有惊无险
but we've had some close calls.
物体 无论其大小
Objects, no matter what their size...
总是处于因轨道衰变被拉出轨道的危险之中
are always in danger of being pulled out of their orbits by orbital decay.
轨道衰变的发生是因为物体丧失速度 由摩擦造成的
Orbital decay occurs when an object loses speed, caused by friction...
开始被引力拉向地球
and begins to be pulled towards Earth by gravity.
大气阻力是轨道衰变的主要原因
Atmospheric drag is the major cause of orbital decay...
就像路上的自行车一样
like a bicyclist on the road.
当你保持速度骑行时
When you're pedaling along at a constant speed...
你保持你的肌肉力量
you're balancing your muscle power...
来对付你骑行中道路施加给轮胎的阻力
against the drag on the tires from the road...
和空气阻力
and the resistance of the air that you're moving through.
你克服那些自行车的阻力
And you overcome that resistance...
靠的是你的肌肉
on a bicycle with your muscles...
而在太空中 要靠点燃你的火箭发动机
or in space by firing your rocket engines...
增加一点速度 来克服空气阻力
to add a little speed, overcome that air resistance.
那就是太空中必须要做的
That's what has to happen in space...
以防止空间站坠落地球燃起大火
to keep the space station from falling back to Earth and burning up.
一旦你停止施加推力 那么空气阻力
And if you stop adding thrust, that air resistance...
最终会减缓到
will eventually slow you down to the point...
你停了下来 坠回大气层返回
where you'll stop or fall back into the atmosphere and re-enter.
有些碎片得以生还
Some pieces survive re-entry...
那些坠落地球的碎片尺寸十分可怕
and the size of these pieces that have fallen to Earth is terrifying.
在过去40年里
In the last 40 years...
有1.7万个太空碎片得以生还
17,000 pieces of space debris have survived re-entry.
早在1997年 我们有一个570磅的不锈钢罐
Back in 1997, we had a 570-pound stainless steel tank...
落在了得克萨斯的一个农户家外的50码处
that landed about 50 yards from a farmer's house in Texas.
他对此并没有特别的高兴
He was not particularly pleased by that.
如果有一件碎片生还
If a piece of debris does survive re-entry...
会以时速120英里的亚音速穿行
it travels at subsonic speeds of 120 miles per hour...
直到撞上地面
until it hits ground.
曾有过闯入南非开普敦的返回
There was a re-entry that came into Cape Town in South Africa.
那是在白天
It was during the day...
有人在田野里劳作
and there were people out working in fields.
他们听到了轰鸣
They heard a sonic boom...
抬头一看
and they looked up...
他们基本上看到了这东西从天而降
and they basically saw this material coming down.
加州埃尔塞贡多航天公司
The Aerospace Corporation in El Segundo, California...
是收集和研究太空垃圾的机构
is a facility that collects and studies space junk...
为军方和私人公司服务
for the military and private companies.
这一件是昔日的太空垃圾
This is a piece of what was once a piece of space junk.
这是火箭级的一部分
This was a part of a rocket stage...
用来将GPS卫星送入轨道
that was used to put a GPS satellite in orbit.
这里你可以看到托架
Here you can see the brackets that were actually melted off...
实际上随着坠落融化了
as this came down.
我们实际上割下了这里的样本 试图了解
We actually have cut samples here to try to understand...
这里发生的情况 温度会有多高
what happened in this area, how hot did it get...
我们利用这些信息来改进我们的模型
and we use that information to improve our models.
搞明白这些碎片是如何生还的
Understanding how these pieces survive re-entry...
对未来的航天器和卫星的建造至关重要
is important for future spacecraft and satellite construction.
回收和再利用关键的航天器部件
Recovering and reusing critical spacecraft parts...
可以节省数百万的制造成本
could save millions in manufacturing costs.
可是 收集太空垃圾却是困难重重
However, collecting space debris remains tricky.
地球表面四分之三是水
Three-quarters of the Earth's surface is water...
因而其大部分坠落在水中
so a lot of it lands in the water.
因此当你在陆地上发现一件
So when you find a piece on the ground...
实际上是非常罕见的事件
it's actually a very rare event.
估计太空垃圾的总量到2050年将翻番
It's estimated the amount of space debris will double by 2050.
但并没有妨碍企业家
But that hasn't deterred entrepreneurs...
继续探索地球轨道作为营业场所
who continue to explore Earth orbit as a business location.
仅仅花上2500美元 太空葬
For a mere $2,500, Memorial Spaceflights...
在2008年开始提供服务
which began service in 2008...
将亲人的骨灰送入近地轨道
will launch ashes of a loved one into low Earth orbit.
这种归宿...
It's a fitting end to anyone...
适合所有梦想有朝一日访问外太空的人
who dreamed of one day visiting outer space.
这只是企业家
This is just one of the many ideas...
开发地球轨道的许多概念之一
entrepreneurs are developing for Earth orbit.
但是要在太空中开展业务
But to run a business in space...
需要有途径来获得长久的占用
there needs to be a way to obtain permanent occupancy.
现在我们进入了21世纪初
Here we are in the early years of the 21st century...
我预计太空正在变成一个产业园
and I foresee space becoming an industrial park.
太空实验室 联盟号 国际空间站
Skylab, Mir, and now the International Space Station...
都提供了一个舞台
have all provided an arena...
在太空中进行长期的居住和实验
for long-term habitation and experiments in space.
若是私人公司也可以拥有围绕地球的航天器又当如何呢?
What if private companies could also have spacecraft orbiting the Earth?
我认为我们过去和现在都是第一家
I think we were and are the first company...
部署了那种结构的公司
to have deployed that kind of structure.
紧挨着拉斯维加斯大道啊
Just off the Las Vegas Strip...
鲍勃.比奇洛及其本杰罗宇航公司的团队
Bob Bigelow and his team at Bigelow Aerospace...
坚持在高度安全的设施里面
are hunkered down in a high-security facility...
打造着新一代宇航器
creating a new generation of spacecraft.
我坚持的童年幻想就是那个
I'm living out a childhood fantasy is what it is.
我认为我们参予了某些很重要的事情
And l think that we are involved in something really important.
私人企业正在探索
Private industry is exploring the opportunities...
我们太空边缘的机会
of our edge of space.
本杰罗宇航公司正在开发充气的工作区
Bigelow Aerospace is developing inflating workspaces...
叫做创世纪 发射到地球轨道上
called Genesis to launch into Earth orbit.
该技术的灵感来自航天局
The technology was inspired by NASA.
我偶尔碰到了一篇技术论文
I came across an article about a technology...
航天局曾研究过的
that NASA had been working on...
我想 噢 天哪 这真了不起
and I thought, "Oh, my God, this is great."
航天局研发了充气的模块 一个叫做转移居住舱的房间
NASA developed an inflatable module, a room called the TransHab.
它将连接空间站
It was going to be joined to the space station...
以提供更多的居住空间
to provide more living space.
航天局一直没有足够的财力来执行该计划
NASA was never able to afford executing that plan.
最后 经过了若干年
Eventually, after a number of years...
我们从航天局收购了他们的专利许可
we acquired the licenses from NASA for their patents.
这概念非常独特
The concept is ingenious.
比奇洛航天器是充气分离舱
Bigelow spacecraft are inflatable pods...
发射过程中可以塞进无人火箭的头部
that tuck into the nose of an unmanned rocket during launch...
然后将旅行尺寸膨胀三倍
then expand to three times their travel size...
充大容积释放入轨
to full capacity once released into orbit.
在火箭过渡时 你只有这么大的体积
In a rocket ferry, you only have so much volume...
如此大的房间就如这个瓶子
so much room like this bottle.
就是这么大
That's as big as it gets. That's it.
但是如果你发射这么大的东西
But if you launch something in that volume...
随后可以膨胀其体积三倍
that can later expand to three times its size...
你就有了更大的房间来派用场了
you have a lot more room to do something with.
我们利用压缩空气来膨胀它到形状
We use compressed gas to expand it into its form.
充气航天器可以适应...
The inflatable spacecraft could be adapted...
任何一位客户的需求
to whatever a client might need--
研究实验室 制造工厂 酒店
research laboratory, manufacturing facility, hotel space--
所有新兴产业都能上地球轨道
all emerging industries for Earth orbit.
我们可以招待各种客户
We can host a variety of different kinds of clients...
他们只需付出...
and they only have to pay for the specific time...
他们参予的具体时间
that they're interested in.
该航天器所用的是
The spacecraft is assembled...
非常耐用但可以弯曲的材料
from very durable but bendable materials...
叫做软优系统
called soft good systems.
你在软优里生活
You've driven all your life on soft goods.
你被赶在轮胎里
You've driven on tires.
充气系统非常可靠 非常坚固
Inflatable systems can be extremely reliable and very strong.
比奇洛并不担心自己的发射系统的可靠性
Bigelow is not worried about the reliability of his launch system.
他使用的第聂伯18火箭
The Dnepr 18 rockets he's using...
完全就是俄罗斯人
are the same ones the Russians trust...
运送他们一些最宝贵荷载的那种
with some of their most precious payloads.
他们有约1100个那样的火箭
They have about 1,100 of those rockets...
现在用在核导弹上
with nuclear missiles on them right now.
我们不会因为火箭的失败而失败
We're not going to fail because the rocket failed.
一旦入轨 仪器装置的能源来自四个太阳能电池板
Once in orbit, instrumentation is powered by four solar panels...
就像国际空间站那样
just like the International Space Station.
创世纪航天器是新一代的空间站
The Genesis spacecraft is a new generation of space station...
可能是政府公债的一大进步
and it might be a vast improvement from the government-issue brand.
我们所致力的东西 就是一旦我们成功
What we're working on, if we're successful...
那可是比呆在铝罐里
is a much safer vessel for humans to be in...
人类更加安全的容器
than the aluminum cans are.
我们的充气容器结构足以
Our inflatable hull structure is adequate...
抵御各种热效应
to protect against any type of thermal effects...
微流星体的防护 辐射效应
micro-meteoroid protection, radiation effects.
本杰罗宇航公司现有两种私人航天器 创世纪1型 2型
Bigelow Aerospace now has two private spacecraft, Genesis I and II...
绕行在地球上空340英里处
orbiting 340 miles above Earth...
独一无二的私人拥有的航天器
the only privately owned spacecraft of their kind...
穿行在太空边缘
orbiting in the edge of space.
发射航天器进入地球轨道只是一个方面挑战
Launching spacecraft into Earth orbit is only one challenge.
选择合适的轨道倾角是另一个挑战
Picking an appropriate inclination for its orbits is another.
轨道面其实只是其
The orientation of an orbit really is just a measure of the degree of tilt...
通过赤道倾角的度量
from the line running through the equator.
你可以有任意选择
You can have anything from zero-degree inclination...
从0度到90度的倾角
to 90-degree inclination.
0度倾角就是与赤道
The zero-degree inclination...
没有任何的倾斜
is absolutely no tilt whatsoever from the equator...
被称为赤道轨道
and that is called an equatorial orbit.
反之 如果你有一个与赤道90度的倾角
Whereas, if you have a 90-degree tilt from the equator...
那就是极轨道
that is a polar orbit.
卫星和航天器根据其任务
Satellites and spacecraft are launched into different inclinations...
发射到不同的倾角
depending on their mission...
因为不同的倾角穿越地球不同的部分
because different inclinations pass over different parts of Earth.
如果你绕着地球
If you're going around the Earth...
绕着赤道 你会看到什么呢?
around the equator, what do you get to see?
就在你下面 会是什么呢?
It's just what's below you, which is going to be what?
赤道
The equator.
那么轨道有个倾角 比方说 56度
So an inclination of the orbit, at, say, 56 degrees...
几乎就能涵盖整个地球
covers almost all of the population of the Earth.
极轨道卫星跑上几圈
A polar orbit satellite has the ability to view the entire Earth...
就能看到整个地球
in a few orbital rotations.
随着地球在下面慢慢旋转
As the Earth slowly rotates below...
卫星在上空持续扫描
the satellite keeps sweeping overhead...
使整个地球在短时间内
allowing the entire Earth to be observed...
被观察到
in a short period of time.
如果任务是间谍或观察
If the mission is for espionage or observation...
太阳同步轨道可以让卫星
Sun-synchronous orbits allow satellites...
在每天同一时间经过地球上的同一个点
to pass over the same point on Earth at the same time every day.
它们每个地球日移动一度
They shift one degree each Earth day...
同步保持在太阳特定位置上
to stay in sync with the Sun at a given location.
如果必须要保持通讯
If constant communication is necessary...
地球同步轨道卫星就被定位在远离地球
geosynchronous satellites are positioned far away from Earth...
这样整个大陆尽收眼底
so that entire continents are within their view.
它与地球的自转一致
It matches the rotation of the Earth...
似乎就盘旋在空中
and appears to hover in the sky.
那是该轨道一个非常有用的特征
That's a very useful trait of that orbit...
因为你可以持续保持无线电或电视
because you can then stay constantly in radio or television touch...
与地面站的联络
with the spot on the ground below.
地球轨道是地球空间活动的...
Earth orbit is the natural extension...
自然延伸
of Earth's occupation in space.
如果未来计划成功的话
And if future plans pan out...
那太空边缘的产业化
the industrialization of the edge of space...
将会发生在不久的将来
will happen in the near future.
也就在40年前 约翰.格伦进入了地球轨道
It was only 40 years ago John Glenn entered Earth orbit.
未来50到100年 把握地球轨道未来的
What the next 50 or 100 years holds for the future of Earth orbit...
将是激动人心的 或许就如月球漫步
is as exciting as perhaps a walk on the Moon...
过去的老一辈那样
once was to an older generation.
本杰罗宇航公司已经到达了一个重要的里程碑
Bigelow Aerospace has already reached a major milestone...
依靠将他们的创世纪1号 2号发射入轨
by launching their Genesis I and II pods into orbit.
但是未来的航天器将是为老百姓打造的
But future spacecraft will be ready for private citizens.
之前谁都没做过
Nobody's done this before.
我的意思是 人们已经进入了太空
I mean, people have gone into space...
但我们所努力的就是使它实用化
but what we're trying to do is make it available.
它叫做追日 300立方米的可居住空间
It's called Sundancer, a 300-cubic-meter inhabitable space...
其容积可以维持三个人无限期居住
that will have the capacity to support up to three human lives indefinitely.
我们必须添加大量的维持生命的设施
We have to add a lot of life-support equipment...
来确保其环境
to make sure that the environment...
可以维持三人组
is sustainable for a crew of three.
要考虑的东西从空调系统
That goes into anything from the air concentration system...
氧气送出 二氧化碳清除
where oxygen has to be delivered, CO2 has to get removed...
一直到更为严格的温度控制和湿度控制
all the way through more rigorous thermal control and humidity control.
一个追日航天器所提供的空间
One Sundancer spacecraft offers more space...
超过了目前的整个国际空间站的能力
than is currently available on the entire International Space Station.
最终 多个航天器将会连接在一块
Eventually, multiple pods will be connected together...
就像万能工匠搭更大的设施那样
like Tinkertoys for larger facilities.
你所选择的形状
What kind of shape you're choosing...
取决于目的 航天器的使命
depends on the purpose, the mission for the spacecraft.
但是犹如开拓者启程跨越浩瀚的大海
But like pioneers setting off across the open sea...
发现新大陆一样 这是个未知的领域
in search of new land, this is uncharted territory.
我们有机会将愿景变为现实
We have an opportunity to turn that vision into a reality...
迄今为止 正是我们所做的
and so far that's exactly what we're doing.
他们是许多梦想...
They are one group of many...
长期入住太空边缘的群体之一
that dream of permanent occupancy at the edge of space.
有一点是清晰明了的
One thing remains clear.
地球需要有简单的方式
Earth needs an easy way...
将航天器 货物 人送上太空
to deliver spacecraft, cargo, and people into space...
去利用地球轨道的优势
to take advantage of Earth orbit...
想法引人入胜
and the ideas are spectacular.
已经有了各种概念
There have been all kinds of concepts...
比如太空电梯
like space elevators.
太空喷泉怎么样
How about a space fountain--
高能粒子波将把货物升入地球轨道
a highly energized wave of particles that lifts cargo up into Earth orbit?
关键在于找到廉价的方法把那些东西送入太空
The key is finding a cheap way to get those materials up to space.
或许可以在环地设施里
Or perhaps the resources of space...
开采太空资源
can be mined in a facility orbiting Earth.
利用月球和附近小行星上的资源
Using the resources that are on the Moon and the asteroids nearby...
来打造太空里的东西
to build things in space themselves.
不必花钱把它们从地面长途运来
Not have to spend the money to haul them up from the ground.
比如 刘易斯和克拉克
For example, Lewis and Clark...
在他们横跨美国大陆时
when they went across the continental U.S...
并没有随身拖着所有的饮用水 柴火
they didn't haul all their drinking water and firewood with them...
从圣路易斯一路往西
from St. Louis on the way west.
他们一路利用他们所找到的东西
They used what they found along the way.
地球轨道最大的礼物有可能是可再生能源
Earth orbit's greatest gift might be sustainable power.
设想一下 一列太阳能电池板
Imagine an array of solar panels...
产生的能量足以点亮整个大陆
that generates enough power to light up a continent.
或许未来50年里 在太空里...
That's probably one of the most promising avenues to pursue...
最有希望追求的途径之一
in the next 50 years in space...
就是找到办法制造出廉价的太阳能收集器
is to find a way to make cheap solar collectors...
然后在地面上建造收集天线
and then build the collecting antennas on the ground...
这样我们就可以使用取之不竭的太阳能
so that we can use inexhaustible solar power...
来减少我们对我们地球上的有限供应的
to reduce our reliance on the finite supplies...
燃料和能源的依赖
of fuel and energy we have here on Earth.
有一点是肯定的:
One thing is certain:
太空边缘是未来探索的切入口
the edge of space is the entryway to future exploration...
是前往整个宇宙的停靠站
a stopping point to the destinations across the universe.
我非常激动 今后几十年里
I'm very excited about a future decades from now...
地球真的会是人类的伊甸园
where the Earth really is the Garden of Eden of humanity...
我们会打理好我们的星球
where we've taken care of our planet...
我们的公园 我们的享受
our parks, our enjoyment...
我们关爱地球要做的就是照顾好它
and the things that we love about the Earth are taken care of.
我们在制造方面所做的一切
And all the things that we do in terms of manufacturing...
资源的开采 能源 采集
and resource extraction and energy and mining...
这些通通都在太空中进行
those things take place in space.
当然 近地轨道一路到整个太阳系
And, of course, low Earth orbit...is the gateway to the rest of the solar system.